# Slim Ouertani June-81, Tunisian

- ouertani@gmail.com (00966)-(0)-583012381 Riyadh (Saudi Arabia)
- linkedin.com/in/ouertani ouertani.github.io twitter.com/ouertani



# CTO, Architect, InfoQ Fr Editor Founder & Organiser of Riyadh IT Architecture Meetup Big Data Science, Cloud & SOA Certified Trainer Togaf, Archimate, IT4IT, SABSA, PMP, Cmmi, ITIL

### Summary

Slim Ouertani is enterprise and solution architect, InfoQ-Fr editor, Big Data Science, Cloud and SOA Certified trainer, founder and organizer of Riyadh IT Architecture Meetup. After his engineer's degree in computer science, Slim spent over than 10 years in multinational companies such as Orange, Sagem and STMicroelectronics as architect, international agile coach and Head of IT development department. His main role was to build, design and collaborate in the development of enterprise solutions.

Slim regularly contributes to InfoQ-FR community where he is the author of many articles and news. you to follow him on twitter @ouertani.

He's broad certified as in addition to his SOA, Cloud and Big Data Science certifications: Trainer, Architect & Engineer, Slim holds multiple certifications including Togaf 9, Archimate 2, IT4IT, SABSA, PMP, ITIL, CMMi, Mongo, Spring, JAVA, SCALA and reactive programming...

Trained as an architect, Slim specializes in enterprise Java development, functional programming focusing on highly scalable applications and now expanding his experience to cloud computing.

Slim enjoys open source contribution and invite

# Experience

Machinestalk	Riyadh, SAUDI ARABIA
CTO	03-2017 – present
	•
Al-Elm Information Security	Riyadh, SAUDI ARABIA
Solution Architect	06-2014-03-2016
Sofrecom (Orange FT Group)	Tunis, Tunisia
Software Architect, International Agile Coach	03-2013 - 06-2014
Zenika	Paris, FRANCE
JEE Architect	12-2012 - 03-2013
Orange	Tunis, Tunisia
Head of Development & Tools Manager	01-2010-11-2012
Sagem Software & Technologies	Tunis, Tunisia
Solution Architect & Team Leader	12-2007 - 01-2010
STMicroelectronics	Tunis, Tunisia
Developer & Coordinator	12-2005 – 12-2007
•	т т
GL TRADE	Tunis, Tunisia
Developer & designer	08-2005 - 12-2005

Please refer to my Linked-in profile for a more complete list of work experiences along with recommendations.

#### Certificate

IT4IT, Open Group	Score 92%, 12-2016
SABSA Charted Architect, SABSA	11-2016
Big Data Science Trainer, Arcitura	09-2016
Bio Data Science Engineer, Arcitura	With Honors, 08-2016

Big Data Professional, Arcitura	With Honors, 05-2016
Archimate Certified, Open Group	Score 82%, 02-2016
Archimate Foundation, Open Group	Score 97%, 02-2016
Cloud Trainer, Arcitura	10-2015
Cloud Architect, Arcitura	With Honors, 10-2015
Cloud Professional, Arcitura	With Honors, 09-2015
Togaf Certified, Open Group	Score 90%, 06-2015
ITIL Foundation, Exin	Score 95%, 06-2015
Togaf Foundation, Open Group	Score 95%, 04-2015
Project Management Professional, PMI	03-2015
SOA Trainer, Arcitura	01-2015
SOA Architect, Arcitura	With Honors, 12-2014
SOA Professional, Arcitura	With Honors, 11-2014
Introduction to Cmmi for development, Cmmi Institute	09-2014
Entrepreneurship for all, EFFECTUATION, EMLYON	Score 75,8%, 01-2014
Principles of Reactive Programming, Coursera	Score 97.5%, 01-2014
MongoDB for DBAs, MongoDB	Score 94%, 11-2013
MongoDb for java, MongoDb	Score 95%, 10-2013
Spring Framework 3, Pivotal	Score 94%, 02-2013
Java 6 Programmer Certified Professional, Oracle	Score 100%, 08-2012
Team Performance, STMicroelectronics	04-2007
English, British Council	4B, 0 <b>2-2</b> 007
GL Certified Professional, GL TRADE	09-2005

#### **Education**

National School of Computer Science ENSI Tunis, Tunisia **Graduation Project in Computer Engineering** 2005 National School of Computer Science ENSI Tunis, Tunisia 2002 - 2005**Engineer Degree in Computer Science** Tunis Preparatory Institute for Engineering StudiesIPEIT Tunis, Tunisia Preparatory Courses (Math Sup, Math Spe) 2000 - 2002Hannibal Ariana, Tunisia 1994 - 2000(Pre-university Secondary Education)

#### Other Activities

## InfoQ Fr Editor

http://www.infoq.com/fr/author/Slim-Ouertani

#### Founder & Organizer

Riyadh IT Architecture Meetup

http://www.meetup.com/Riyadh-IT-Architecture

#### **BLOGGGING**

http://java.dzone.com/users/slim.ouertani

http://ouertani.github.io

http://www.jroller.com/ouertani
http://twitter.com/ouertani

#### **INTERVIEW**

Paremus, SCA with OSGI, David Savage

http://www.prosyst.com/

07.02.2009

http://goo.gl/H5yJzY

# MAGAZINE

From Microservices to SOA - 20.07.2015 Service Technology Magazine - Issue XCI http://servicetechmag.com/I91/0715-1

#### **OPEN SOURCE**

https://github.com/ouertani http://www.reactive-streams.org

# **STAMPLE**

https://stample.co Scala, Akka, Play ElasticSearch, MongoDb, Amazon S3, GreenCloud

# **Arcitura Authorized Training Partner**

http://www.arcitura.com/ Big Data Science, Cloud & SOA

# **Publications**

23.07.2015
25.11.2014
29.07.2014
30.06.2014
02.06.2014
18.04.2014
01.11.2013
16.10.2013
18.02.2013
11.02.2013

*Please refer to my Linked-in profile for a more complete list of publications since 2008.* 

# News

Publication de la Nouvelle Spécification d'ArchiMate 3.0	22.06.2016
Java EE et les Anges Gardiens	11.05.2016
Microservice antipatterns à Qcon London 2016	14.04.2016
MongoDB: la magie des Reactive-Streams avec les Capped Collections	21.05.2015
Publication de l'API Reactive Streams 1.0	07.05.2015
Docker, le dernier clou dans le cercueil des serveurs d'applications Java?	19.03.2015

# Languages

Arabic, French English

Written & Spoken